译者:微博@Emtee
雅各布
Jakob.
你在那吗 雅各布
Are you there, Jakob?
你在听吗
Are you listening?
雅各布
Jakob.
我在这里
I'm here.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
别 - 嘘 嘘
Don't. - Shh, shh.
安静
Be silent.
听我说
And hear me.
必须这样
This is how it must be.
另一个女人会来
Another woman will come.
你会看到
You will see.
会有另一个
There will be another.
你会因她给你的爱
You will know her
而了解她
by the love she shows to you.
让你讲出的话
Let the words you speak
变成唤我回你身边的言语
be the words that call me back to you.
向我保证
Promise me.
保证
Promise.
雅各布
Jakob.
我会永远是你的母亲
I will always be your mother.
墙里的声音
译者:微博@Emtee
你的推荐信
我们真的极其感激你做的一切
谢谢 我恐怕我必须赶路了
你要去哪
我必须走了 因为你好起来了
你不再需要我
我当然需要你
不需要
No.
你需要的是你的妈妈和爸爸
卡洛塔
Carlotta.
我会一直想你
请别走
别离开我
卡洛塔 - 再见
Carlotta... - Arrivederci.
我几乎不认识我看到的这个女人
I hardly know the woman I see.
她叫维拉娜
Her name is verena.
她孤身一人
She is alone.
每一次分别
She remembers all of them.
她都记得
Every parting.
她的人生由离别组成
Her life is measured out in good-byes.
一次比一次难
Each one harder than the last.
来到拉罗丘萨
Enter la rocciosa...
来到不说话的男孩身边
And the boy who wouldn't speak.
你好
我叫维拉娜
我相信有人盼着我
我为那男孩而来
抱歉 先生
我搞错约见时间了吗
没有
我肯定职位还空着
没错 要一个说英语的护工
那是我的母语
My first language.
这些是我前几任雇主写的
I have these from previous employers.
你每一家都住下吗 - 是的
Did you live with each family? - Yes.
我觉得这样有助于通过理解孩子
I find it helps in understanding the child
来了解家庭
to know the family.
你和这些人还联系吗
And do you remain in contact with these people?
孩子康复后 家人
When a child recovers, the family
一般会选择遗忘
will generally choose to forget.
你没学位
You've no degree.
但他们说你有天赋
But they say you've a gift.
我的能力来自经验
My skill comes through experience
和某种敏锐感
and a certain, um, sensitivity.
敏锐感
Sensitivity.
你自己都没孩子
You have no children of your own.
是的
No.
你的儿子
Your son.
他喜欢英语?
He prefers English?
他的母亲
His mother.
我的妻子想要他讲英语
My wife wanted him to speak it.
她死了 因为患了种病
She died. There was an illness.
自那以后 我儿子就没说过话
My son has not spoken since.
已经七个月
Seven months...
十六天了
And sixteen days.
阿莱西奥会带你去你的房间
Alessio will see you to your room.
我想向你的儿子
I would like to introduce myself
自我介绍下
to your son.
你还没告诉我他的名字
You haven't told me his name.
我得说 之前的护工
I must say there have been other nurses,
对她们的能力都和你一样自信
all of them as sure of their talents as you.
我儿子叫雅各布
My son's name is Jakob.
你好 雅各布
Hello, Jakob.
我叫维拉娜
My name is verena,
我要在这住一阵子
and I'm going to be staying here for a while.
我保证我和其他护工不一样
I promise I'm not like the others.
我差劲多了
I'm much worse.
请看着我 雅各布
Please look at me, Jakob.
我想帮助你 明白吗
I'd like to help you. Do you understand?
没用
There's no point.
他甚至都不点头
He won't even nod his head.
他不写字 不画画
He won't write or draw...
不唱歌 不大笑
Sing or laugh...
不微笑
Smile...
不哭泣
Cry.
谢谢
Grazie.
我们早上开始沟通 雅各布
We'll begin our work in the morning, Jakob.
9点如何
Say 9:00?
你问了也白问
Your questions are wasted.
雅各布不用回答我
Jakob doesn't need to answer me.
我觉得他明白
I think he understands that.
够了
Enough.
坐下
Sit down.
现在你可以走了
Now you may go.
晚安 雅各布
Good night, Jakob.
他很听话
He is very obedient.
这跟讲不讲话有关
This is part of it.
不听话就得讲话 所以
To disobey is to say something, so...
所以他听话
So he obeys.
他不想让你伤心
He isn't trying to hurt you.
他是我儿子 小姐 而不是我
That's my son, signorina, not me.
雅各布不希望你在这
Jakob doesn't want you here.
他还没表现出来 但他会的
He hasn't shown it yet, but he will.
他的沉默有很强的力量
There is such power in his silence.
你会感受到
You will feel it.
你对他讲话很严厉
You speak very harshly to him.
你比其他护工胆子大
Braver than the others.
我有事要问
I have some things i need to ask.
什么事
What things?
或许明天再问吧
Tomorrow, perhaps.
首先 我要告诉你我的看法
To begin with, I will tell you what I see.
就是
I see...
你想说话的话
That if you wanted to speak,
你可以说
you could.
我也知道 真的什么都不说
Hmm, and I see how hard it must be
是有多不容易
to truly say nothing...
你必须时刻专注是有多不容易
How hard you must be concentrating every moment.
我必须承认 你非常擅长这样
And I must admit, you're very good at it.
与世隔绝的感觉
I know a little something of what it feels
我懂
to be apart from the world.
我比你小点时 失去了母亲
I lost my mother when I was a little bit younger than you...
再大点时 失去了父亲
And my father when I was a little bit older.
今天天气不错
It's a lovely day.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
雅各布
Jakob?
Jakob!
早上好
Buongiorno.
我在找雅各布
你已经找不到他了?
你见到他
请告诉他我有话跟他说
谢谢
Grazie.
雅各布
Jakob?
请原谅  我不...
Oh. Please forgive me. I didn't--
维拉娜
verena.
那个护工
The nurse, of course.
靠近点
Come closer.
让莉莉娅看看你
Let Lilia see you.
你是来让那孩子说话的
You've come to make the boy talk.
我只是尽我所能
Just to help if I can.
欢迎
Oh, welcome.
Welcome.
欢迎来到拉罗丘萨 孩子
Welcome to la rocciosa, my child.
谢谢
Grazie.
你真好
You're very kind.
但我该走了
But I should go.
当然 去找那个男孩
Yes, of course. Go find the boy.
让他说话
Make him talk.
抱歉 我在找雅各布
I'm sorry. I-i was looking for Jakob.
你会弹吗
Do you play?
不会 从没弹过
No, I, uh, never could.
这是你的妻子?
This is your wife?
是的
Yes.
她叫什么
What was her name?
今早你和雅各布待在一起
You spent time with Jakob this morning.
是的
Yes.
你有没注意到什么
And did you observe anything?
我需要了解他经历了什么
I need to understand what he has been through.
玛尔维娜
Malvina.
玛尔维娜·里维
Malvina rivi.
你可能听说过她
You may have heard of her.
没
No.
那是卡耐基音乐厅
That's carnegie hall.
她在全世界所有的伟大音乐厅演奏过
She played all over the world, in all the great halls,
为国王 王后
for kings and queens,
总统演奏
presidents.
她很漂亮
She was very beautiful.
拍完这张照片的六个月后
Six months after that photograph was taken,
她死了
she was dead.
这一切开始于我们回来之后
It began after our return.
起初是纯发烧
It started as a simple fever
后来烫得像火
and became like fire.
她的力气 她的美貌
Each day, it consumed a little bit more
每一天 都在被
of her strength,
一点点地消耗
her beauty.
我不得不离开 去寻求帮助
I had to leave to find help,
雅各布陪着她
and Jakob stayed with her.
他和莉莉娅一起护理她
He and Lilia nursed her together.
他不愿离开他的母亲
He wouldn't leave his mother's side.
他有他母亲的天赋
He has his mother's gift.
他们会坐在这 一起弹上数小时
They would sit here and play together for hours.
他选择不说话?
He chooses not to speak?
这一定是
Oh, this--this must be
你那令人难以置信的敏锐感?
that incredible sensitivity of yours?
我的意思是 身体没受过伤?
I mean, there is no injury?
没机能不全?
No incapacity?
他的内心已经破碎了
Something inside him has been broken.
这纯粹是抗拒
It is simply a refusal...
是不想接受
A denial...tяаńsξаtεd ьy щεìьδ Εmtεε
如此看来
As if, by this vigil...
解铃还须系铃人
He can undo what is done.
你是在跟我说  他希望他的母亲回来?
You're telling me he wants his mother back, hmm?
真是意外的发现
Well, that's a-- that's a revelation.
我一直在找你 雅各布
I've--I've been looking for you, Jakob.
我是来工作
I'm here to work,
不是来玩捉迷藏的
not to play hide-and-seek.
你有跟雅各布说我在找他吗
没
No.
我忘了
我还没说完呢 雅各布
I haven't finished yet, Jakob.
我们有事要做
你们家非常漂亮
You have a very beautiful home.
谢谢
Thank you.
我真心希望你在这会住得舒服
I do hope you'll be comfortable here.
雅各布 有次
Once, Jakob,
我住在卢卡的一家人家里
I stayed with a family in lucca.
他们的房子有10年
Their house hadn't been cleaned
没打扫过
in years.
那里的蟑螂和你父亲的手表一样大
There were cockroaches as big as your father's watch.
有次 我住在皮亚琴察的一家人家里
And once, I stayed with a family in piacenza.
我和厨师同房
I shared a room with the cook
那人打起鼾就像水牛
who snored come un bufalo.
所以  我肯定
So, yes, I'm sure...
我在这会住得非常舒服
I will be very comfortable here.
说实话 我不能把这地方当成是我自己的
In truth, I cannot think of this place as my own.
我妻子的家族在这住了有1200年
My wife's family has lived here for 1,200 years.
我只是个访客
I'm just a visitor.
阿莱西奥的家族在这也同样那么久
Alessio's family has been here for just as long.
女人们在室内干活
The women work here in the house.
男人们则在采石场
The men, in the quarry.
采石场?
The quarry?
那里是这一切的来源
It's where all this comes from,
是这家族的财富
the wealth of the family.
石头曾极为珍贵
The stone was once highly prized.
曾?
Was?
大战之初 她允许那里让水淹了
She allowed it to flood at the beginning of the war.
那时的日子不好过
Times were difficult.
而且她有她的事业
And she had her career.
不再需要石头了
No more need for the stone.
雅各布会在那游泳
Jakob swims there.
你想去的话 他会带你去
He'll take you there if you wish.
没错
Yes.
我非常想去
I'd like that very much.
你好
Salve.
少爷没事的
你确定吗
水挺深
非常深
这是干嘛的
纪念那些曾在采石场干活的人
那些因为石头死去的人
生 死 爱
石头曾是一切
让我来...
Let me.
请让我来
Per favore.
已经好久没这样了
It's been so long.
我...
I...
从她很小的时候开始
Used to do this to her
在她生活中的每个晚上
every night of her life...
都给她梳
Since she was a tiny girl.
她十四岁时
She began to perform
就开始演奏了
when she was fourteen.
她带着我到处走
She took me with her everywhere.
没人像我一样了解她
Nobody knew her as I did...
了解她的心情
Knew her moods,
她的需求
her needs.
没人知道我有多爱她
How I loved her.
雅各布 是你干的吗
Jakob, was it you?
是的话  那你做的一切就说明你害怕了
If it was, then all you've done is tell me you're afraid.
雅...
Ja...
雅各布
Jakob.
雅各布 怎么了
Jakob, what is it?
雅各布
Jakob.
怎么了
What?
雅各布 别
Jakob, no!
等等
Wait! Wait!
雅各布
Jakob?
嘿
Hey!
雅各布
Jakob.
雅各布 别
Jakob, no.
安静 安静
Quiet. Quiet.
Be quiet. Be quiet.
安静
Quiet.
够了
Enough.
别动
Stop!
我本该离开的
I should have left him.
他靠在墙上 就好像是在...
He was by the wall as if he was...
聆听
Listening.
是的 我见他这么做过
Yes, I've seen him do it.
在他的卧室
In his bedroom.
还有在花园
Also in the garden.
在采石场
In the quarry.
我猜他听到的是他母亲
I assume it's his mother he hears
或是他以为他听到的是
or thinks he hears.
这似乎能安慰他
It seems to give him comfort.
你早该告诉我
I should have been told.
这让情况变得不同
It changes the situation.
这可能表明他有更严重的症状
It may indicate a far more serious condition.
你不信有那种声音?
You don't believe in such voices?
不信
No.
先生 我不信
No, signore, I do not.
我也不信
Nor do I.
有时我希望我信
Sometimes I wish I did.
你有没考虑过
Have you considered
把他带离这地方
taking him away from this place?
当然有
Yes, of course.
这不可能
It was impossible.
如你昨晚所见
It was as you saw last night.
他对自己和别人会变得有危险性
He became a danger to himself and to others.
那他应该进医院
Then he should be in hospital.
绝对不行
No, absolutely not.
不行
No.
先生 我不再确定我能照顾你儿子
Signore, I'm no longer sure i can care for your son.
为什么
Why?
我一直在被这里的需求误导
I have been misled about what is required.
我必须考虑下我是否有相应资质
I must consider whether I am properly qualified.
你就和其他护工一样
You're just like the others.
我等你决定
I await your decision.
雅各布
Jakob.
雅各布 雅各布
Jakob! Jakob!
搀我下来
Help me down.
你吓到我了 雅各布
You scared me, Jakob.
但你帮我想明白了
But you've helped me realize something.
我不能离你而去
I can't leave you.
我以前认识个男孩
I once knew a boy
他认为他能用一把旧梳上的梳齿
who thought he could hear his dead sister
听到他死去的妹妹
through the teeth of an old comb.
他会拿着它坐上数小时
He would sit with it for hours,
聆听并低语他的秘密
listening and whispering his secrets.
他和你一样 确信听到了声音
He was as sure of what he heard as you are.
头脑能做出不寻常的事
The mind is capable of extraordinary things.
是你的大脑在和你讲话 雅各布
It is your mind that is speaking to you, Jakob,
而不是别的
nothing else.
我不是说
I'm not saying that...
你听到的不是真实的
That what you hear isn't real,
因为我们经历的任何事都是按其自身的方式真实存在的
because anything we experience is real in its own way,
但那...
but it's...
那不是装出来的
It's not what it pretends to be.
理解这一点很重要
It's important to understand that.
我想听到你说话
I want to hear you speak.
但我不是你的敌人
But I am not your enemy.
我关心你
I care about you.
怎么了
What is it?
你想出去?
You wish to leave?
这是什么地方
家族墓地
进去看看吧
雅各布
Jakob?
整个家族都在这里
四十代人
都被葬在这 都在石头里
卢西亚
Lucia...
乌格丽娜
Ugolina ...
安吉莉卡
Angelica...
玛尔维娜夫人
La signora malvina.
雅各布
Jakob?
请跟我来
Come with me, please.
你说的越少 听到的就越多
我什么都没听到
我想你怕自己说话了
I think you're afraid that if you speak,
声音就会停止
the voice will cease.
来
Come.
我们去一起听
We'll listen together.
我会告诉你我听到了什么
I'll tell you what I hear.
好奇怪...
It's strange...
那些声音
The sounds.
让人能想象几乎所有一切
One could imagine almost anything.
但她不在那
But she's not there.
我希望你别再这样
I want you to stop this.
死人不会说话
The dead do not speak.
我知道的 雅各布
I know it, Jakob.
我很清楚
I know it well.
无论我们多么希望死人说话
However hard we wish them to,
他们永远是沉默的
the dead remain silent.
晚安 雅各布
Good night, Jakob.
你父亲告诉我你有她的天赋
Your father told me you have her gift.
她要是知道你可能永远不会再弹 她会怎么说
What would she say if she knew you might never use it again?
她一定在死前
She must have spoken about the future
讲过将来
before she died...
讲过你将面对的美好
About the wonderful things that lie ahead for you.
想想她说的话
Try to remember what she said.
想象下 她现在要是能看见你 她会说什么
And imagine what she might say now if she could see you.
早上好
Buongiorno.
先生
Signore.
那只猫有个故事
There's a story about that cat.
这里的房屋有个习俗 就如这栋
It was the custom amongst those building houses such as this
把一只猫封墙里
to--to seal a cat within the walls
来抵御邪恶
as a protection against evil.
一只死猫?
A dead cat?
不是
No.
没死
Not dead.
那太可怕了
That's horrible.
当然
Of course.
我真蠢 说得这么轻率
I-I'm a fool to speak lightly of it.
请原谅
Forgive me.
雅各布在等着 - 没错
Jakob will be waiting. - Yes.
现在如果你要弹
now, if you were to play,
那就只代表是你的想法
it would mean only what you wanted it to mean.
为我弹吧 雅各布
Play for me, Jakob.
之前我谈到你母亲时 或许我错了
Perhaps I was wrong earlier when I spoke about your mother.
或许你的沉默
Perhaps your silence
不会让她像我一样震骇
wouldn't horrify her as it does me.
据说 真正的演奏者
It is said that a true performer
只在意她听众的爱
cares only for the love of her audience.
或许
Perhaps...
你的沉默是份合适的献礼
Your silence is a fitting tribute.
她离开了舞台 更让人敬爱
More adoration as she leaves the stage.
你想跟我说什么 雅各布
What are you telling me, Jakob--
我说错了 还是我说对了
that I'm wrong or that I'm right?
你不能…
You can t--
我这样是为了帮你 雅各布
I do it to help you, Jakob.
那男孩今天不开心
The boy was upset today.
他病了
He's sick.
他需要帮助
He needs help.
他在伤他父亲的心
And he's breaking his father's heart.
那男孩...
The boy...
至关重要
Is all that matters.
他是未来
He is the future.
看看你自己
Look at yourself...
你是多么美丽
How beautiful you are.
伸出双手
Give me your hands.
好强健
They're strong,
和她的一样
like hers.
他不会用讲话来取悦你
He will not speak to please you.
等时机成熟 那男孩才会讲话
The boy will speak when the time is right.
他在等待
He's waiting.
但他等得够久了
But he's waited long enough.
显然大家都清楚
Surely that is clear to anyone.
等他讲话了
When he speaks...
你会去哪
Where will you go?
下一个地方
To the next place.
孤独的孩子
Lonely child.
墙里的那只猫有个故事
There's a story about that cat within the walls.
他在等待
He's waiting.
我想知道雅各布还在不在这里
I wondered if Jakob was still here.
不在了
No.
我能看看吗
May I see?
想看就看吧
If you wish.
这是我的妻子
It's my wife.
她是最糟的模特
She was the worst possible model--
不耐烦 爱抱怨
restless, complaining.
她是最糟的
She was the worst
也是最好的
and also the best.
这个呢
And this one?
我好几个月没弄了
I have not worked in many months.
这本来会是她
It was to be of her.
你没法完成 所以把它遗弃了
You cannot finish it, so you abandoned it.
或许看你干活
Perhaps to see you work,
会帮到雅各布
it would help Jakob.
也许它象征着希望
Perhaps it would signify hope.
是啊
Yes.
也许吧
Perhaps.
玛尔维娜
有人吗
Hello?
莉莉娅
Lilia?
我一直帮她保持干净
I keep it clean for her.
她死前就在这里
She was here at the end.
我们不舍昼夜地护理她
We nursed her day and night...
我和那个男孩
Me and the boy.
他看到了可怕的事
He saw terrible things.
他听到了...
He heard...
可怕的东西
Terrible things.
她死后 我清洗了她...
When she died, I washed her...
整理了她的头发
A-and tidied her hair.
这房间让你心神不宁
The room upsets you.
你的衣服破了
Oh, you've torn your dress.
是的
Uh, yes.
是的 不知道我能否借些线
Yes, i-i wondered if I might borrow some thread.
我有个主意
I have an idea.
不行
Oh, no.
No, no, i-i couldn't.
等下
Wait.
真不行
I ca--i really-- please, I really can't.
我看看 这件
Let's see. This?
不行
No.
试试这件
Try this on.
看看合不合身
See how it fits, huh?
太好了 真漂亮
Brava. Bellisima.
完美
Ah, perfetto.
真漂亮
Bellisima.
我的衣服...我的裙子破了
I-i-i tore my dre--my skirt.
脱掉
Take it off.
好的
Yes.
别
No.
穿上
Put it on.
把那件放好
Put that one away.
先生
Signore.
请进
Please.
我有事相求
I have something to ask.
你很可能会拒绝
You may very likely refuse.
什么事
What is it?
今天下午 我看到了
I saw this afternoon
我之前没注意的地方
something I had previously failed to notice,
你...你和我妻子之间
certain resemblances between you...
有某些相似之处
You and my wife.
我...
I...
我想你知道我的请求是什么
I-i think you know what it is I ask.
我若有所冒犯 我道歉
If I have offended you, i apologize
也请你彻底忘了这件事
and ask that we forget the matter entirely.
你在这的工作不会受到影响
Your work here will be unaffected.
看看你自己
Look at yourself,
你是多么美丽
how beautiful you are.
左腿往前
Your left leg forward.
你的手
Your hand.
没错 就是这样
Yes, your hand.
你的头
Your head.
这边 没错
This way, yes.
再过来一点
Just a little more.
别动
Don't move.
带他们进来
Bring them in.
雅各布
Jakob.
我在这里
I'm here.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
雅各布
Jakob.
我会照顾你
I'm going to look after you.
我保证
I promise.
你在让他伤心
You're hurting him now.
让我来照顾他
Let me care for him.
让我来照顾他们父子
Let me care for them both.
抱歉
谢谢送花来
这是她最喜欢的颜色
译{}者{}:{}微{}博{}@{}E{}m{}t{}e{}e
这是她
Is it her?
还是我
Or is it me?
你想见我?
You wanted to see me?
我想是时候
I think it's time for us
审查下你的工作进展了
to review the progress of your work,
并讨论下雅各布的行为有没什么变化
to discuss any changes in Jakob's behavior.
他需要我
He needs me.
我能帮助他
I can help him.
然而他仍然什么也不说
And yet he has still said nothing.translated by weibo - Emtee
我是要保护他
It's for me to protect him,
现在我却把事情弄得更糟了
and now I have made things worse.
她想要我在这
She wants me here...
照顾雅各布
To take care of Jakob and...
照顾你
And to take care of you.
那声音是真实的
The voice is real.
你疯了
You're mad.
没错
Yes.
你自己说的
You said it yourself--
严重的症状
serious condition.
我本该多加留意
I should have paid closer attention.
你没在帮助雅各布 而是让你自己出了问题
Instead of helping Jakob, you've made yourself unwell.
现在你能听到你想听的了
Now you hear whatever you wish.
不是 - 是的
No. - Yes.
她为什么要跟你说话 而不是跟她丈夫说
Why would she speak to you and not to her husband?
请别把我送走 求你了
Please don't send me away. Please.
我必须做对雅各布
I must do what is best,
最有利的事
above all, for Jakob.
雅各布
Jakob!
Jakob.
他打算把我送走
He's going to send me away.
告诉我 我该怎么做
Tell me what I must do.
告诉我
Tell me.
告诉我 告诉我
Tell me. Tell me.
告诉我
Tell me.
告诉我 告诉我
Tell me! Tell me!
Tell me. Tell me.
告诉我
Tell me!
雅各布
Jakob.
另一个女人会来
Another woman will come.
必须这样
This is how it must be.
我们必须帮她
We must help her.
雅各布
Jakob.
雅各布 仔细听我说
Jakob, listen to me closely.
你母亲守护着你
Your mother is watching over you.
但她遭受着痛苦
But she is suffering.
她累了
She is tired.
她被困住了
And she is trapped.
雅各布
Jakob,
我们必须帮她
we must help her.
We must help her.
你知道你必须做什么
You know what you must do.
雅各布
Jakob.
雅各布 雅各布
Jakob. Jakob!
雅各布 停下
Jakob, stop!
雅各布
Jakob!
停下 雅各布
Stop, Jakob!
雅各布 别
Jakob, no.
别
No, no, no.
是时候了
It's time.
你必须放下她
You have to let her go.
别 雅各布
No. Jakob.
必须是这个时候
No, it has to be now.
明白吗
Do you understand?
你不讲话 他就会把我送走
He will send me away if you don't speak.
讲话
Speak.
讲话 讲话
Speak! Speak!
讲话
Speak!
不
No.
雅各布
Jakob.
必须这样
This is how it must be.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我得走了 - 不行
I must leave. - No.
先生 她把她的病传给了我
Sir, she's given me her illness.
你发烧了 仅此而已
You have a fever. That is all.
你不用走
You don't have to leave.
我希望你留下
I want you to stay.
原谅我 我们因她迷乱太久了
Forgive me. We've been under her spell too long--
不只是雅各布 我们都是
not only Jakob, all of us.
不行
I can't.
雅各布需要你
No, Jakob needs you.
求你了
Please.
我很害怕
I'm so afraid.
莉莉娅 她在哪
Lilia--where is she?
谁
Who?
莉莉娅
Lilia.
什么意思
What do you mean?
她在哪
Where is she?
她死了
She's dead.
在玛尔维娜的葬礼当天
On the day of malvina's funeral,
她把石头放进口袋 走入了湖中
she put stones in her pockets and walked into the lake.
维拉娜
Verena.
Verena!
看看你自己
Look at yourself.
这里可不行
Not here.
这房间可不行
Not this room.
别
No. No, no, no.
No, no, no.
这房间可不行
Not this room.
没事的
It's all right.
喝完
Tutto.
Tutto, tutto.
门之前被锁了
The door was locked.
这是为了你的安全
It's for your safety.
求你了 克劳斯 这房间可不行
Please, Klaus, not this room.
阿莱西奥觉得迷迷糊糊最好
Alessio think it's best to confuse, confuse.
请别把我留在这
Please don't leave me here.
我要去请个医生
I'm going to fetch a doctor,
他会尽快赶来
and he'll be here as soon as he can.
请别把我留在这
Don't leave me here.
这房间可不行
Not this room.
我必须跟雅各布说话
I must speak to Jakob.
雅各布
Jakob.
等时机成熟
The boy will speak
那男孩才会讲话
when the time is right.
救我
Help me.
Help.
请救救我
Help me.
天呐 别这样
Oh, god, please.
早上好
Good morning.
你感觉好些没
You're feeling better?
一切都会好起来 我保证
Everything's going to be fine. I promise.
我本来还挺担心
I was worried.
雅各布在哪
Where is Jakob?
我想我妈妈
I miss my mama.
我在这里
I'm here.
我就在这里
I'm right here.
雅各布
Jakob.
我试图回想前一段时间
I try to think of a time before this.
我几乎不认识我看到的这个女人
I hardly know the woman I see.
但过去是一场梦 每个新晨 我们会从中醒来
But the past is a dream from which we wake with each new morning.
我们都不是过去的我们
we are, none of us, quite who we were.
过来 雅各布
Come, Jakob.
坐我旁边
Sit with me.
译者:微博@Emtee
愿留译者信息的压制站 请发个联系邮箱至 subcourier@outlook.com 来信请注明站点